Reporting a Bug

Whenever you find a bug in Symfony, we kindly ask you to report it. It helps us make a better Symfony.

Caution

If you think you’ve found a security issue, please use the special procedure instead.

Before submitting a bug:

Double-check the official documentation to see if you’re not misusing the framework;

Ask for assistance on Stack Overflow [https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/symfony], on the #support channel of the Symfony Slack [https://symfony.com/slack-invite] or on the #symfony IRC channel [https://symfony.com/irc] if you’re not sure if your issue really is a bug.

If your problem definitely looks like a bug, report it using the official bug tracker [https://github.com/symfony/symfony/issues] and follow some basic rules:

Use the title field to clearly describe the issue;

Describe the steps needed to reproduce the bug with short code examples (providing a unit test that illustrates the bug is best);

If the bug you experienced is not simple or affects more than one layer, providing a simple failing unit test may not be sufficient. In this case, please provide a reproducer;

Give as much detail as possible about your environment (OS, PHP version, Symfony version, enabled extensions, …);

If there was an exception and you would like to report it, it is valuable to provide the stack trace for that exception. If you want to provide a stack trace you got on an HTML page, be sure to provide the plain text version, which should appear at the bottom of the page. Do not provide it as a screenshot, since search engines will not be able to index the text inside them. Same goes for errors encountered in a terminal, do not take a screenshot, but copy/paste the contents. If the stack trace is long, consider enclosing it in a <details> HTML tag [https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/details]. Be wary that stack traces may contain sensitive information, and if it is the case, be sure to redact them prior to posting your stack trace.

(optional) Attach a patch.

Symfony Core Team

The Symfony Core team is the group of developers that determine the direction and evolution of the Symfony project. Their votes rule if the features and patches proposed by the community are approved or rejected.

All the Symfony Core members are long-time contributors with solid technical expertise and they have demonstrated a strong commitment to drive the project forward.

This document states the rules that govern the Symfony core team. These rules are effective upon publication of this document and all Symfony Core members must adhere to said rules and protocol.

Core Organization

Symfony Core members are divided into groups. Each member can only belong to one group at a time. The privileges granted to a group are automatically granted to all higher priority groups.

The Symfony Core groups, in descending order of priority, are as follows:

Project Leader

Elects members in any other group;

Merges pull requests in all Symfony repositories.

Mergers Team

Merge pull requests on the main Symfony repository.

In addition, there are other groups created to manage specific topics:

Security Team

Manage the whole security process (triaging reported vulnerabilities, fixing the reported issues, coordinating the release of security fixes, etc.)

Recipes Team

Manage the recipes in the main and contrib recipe repositories.

Documentation Team

Manage the whole symfony-docs repository [https://github.com/symfony/symfony-docs].

Active Core Members

Project Leader:

Fabien Potencier (fabpot [https://github.com/fabpot/]).

Mergers Team (@symfony/mergers on GitHub):

Nicolas Grekas (nicolas-grekas [https://github.com/nicolas-grekas/]);

Christophe Coevoet (stof [https://github.com/stof/]);

Christian Flothmann (xabbuh [https://github.com/xabbuh/]);

Tobias Schultze (Tobion [https://github.com/Tobion/]);

Kévin Dunglas (dunglas [https://github.com/dunglas/]);

Jakub Zalas (jakzal [https://github.com/jakzal/]);

Javier Eguiluz (javiereguiluz [https://github.com/javiereguiluz/]);

Grégoire Pineau (lyrixx [https://github.com/lyrixx/]);

Ryan Weaver (weaverryan [https://github.com/weaverryan/]);

Robin Chalas (chalasr [https://github.com/chalasr/]);

Maxime Steinhausser (ogizanagi [https://github.com/ogizanagi/]);

Samuel Rozé (sroze [https://github.com/sroze]);

Yonel Ceruto (yceruto [https://github.com/yceruto]);

Tobias Nyholm (Nyholm [https://github.com/Nyholm]);

Wouter De Jong (wouterj [https://github.com/wouterj]);

Alexander M. Turek (derrabus [https://github.com/derrabus/]);

Jérémy Derussé (jderusse [https://github.com/jderusse/]);

Titouan Galopin (tgalopin [https://github.com/tgalopin/]).

Security Team (@symfony/security on GitHub):

Fabien Potencier (fabpot [https://github.com/fabpot/]);

Michael Cullum (michaelcullum [https://github.com/michaelcullum]);

Jérémy Derussé (jderusse [https://github.com/jderusse/]).

Recipes Team:

Fabien Potencier (fabpot [https://github.com/fabpot/]);

Tobias Nyholm (Nyholm [https://github.com/Nyholm]).

Documentation Team (@symfony/team-symfony-docs on GitHub):

Fabien Potencier (fabpot [https://github.com/fabpot/]);

Ryan Weaver (weaverryan [https://github.com/weaverryan/]);

Christian Flothmann (xabbuh [https://github.com/xabbuh/]);

Wouter De Jong (wouterj [https://github.com/wouterj]);

Jules Pietri (HeahDude [https://github.com/HeahDude]);

Javier Eguiluz (javiereguiluz [https://github.com/javiereguiluz/]).

Oskar Stark (OskarStark [https://github.com/OskarStark]).

Former Core Members

They are no longer part of the core team, but we are very grateful for all their Symfony contributions:

Bernhard Schussek (webmozart [https://github.com/webmozart/]);

Abdellatif AitBoudad (aitboudad [https://github.com/aitboudad/]);

Romain Neutron (romainneutron [https://github.com/romainneutron]);

Jordi Boggiano (Seldaek [https://github.com/Seldaek/]);

Lukas Kahwe Smith (lsmith77 [https://github.com/lsmith77/]).

Core Membership Application

At present, new Symfony Core membership applications are not accepted.

Core Membership Revocation

A Symfony Core membership can be revoked for any of the following reasons:

Refusal to follow the rules and policies stated in this document;

Lack of activity for the past six months;

Willful negligence or intent to harm the Symfony project;

Upon decision of the Project Leader.

Should new Symfony Core memberships be accepted in the future, revoked members must wait at least 12 months before re-applying.

Code Development Rules

Symfony project development is based on pull requests proposed by any member of the Symfony community. Pull request acceptance or rejection is decided based on the votes cast by the Symfony Core members.

Pull Request Voting Policy

-1 votes must always be justified by technical and objective reasons;

+1 votes do not require justification, unless there is at least one -1 vote;

Core members can change their votes as many times as they desire during the course of a pull request discussion;

Core members are not allowed to vote on their own pull requests.

Pull Request Merging Policy

A pull request can be merged if:

It is a minor change 1;

Enough time was given for peer reviews;

At least two Merger Team members voted +1 (only one if the submitter is part of the Merger team) and no Core member voted -1 (via GitHub reviews or as comments).

Pull Request Merging Process

All code must be committed to the repository through pull requests, except for minor changes 1 which can be committed directly to the repository.

Mergers must always use the command-line gh tool provided by the Project Leader to merge the pull requests.

Release Policy

The Project Leader is also the release manager for every Symfony version.

Symfony Core Rules and Protocol Amendments

The rules described in this document may be amended at anytime at the discretion of the Project Leader.

1(1,2)

Minor changes comprise typos, DocBlock fixes, code standards violations, and minor CSS, JavaScript and HTML modifications.

Maintenance

During the lifetime of a minor version, new releases (patch versions) are published on a monthly basis. This document describes the boundaries of acceptable changes.

Bug fixes are accepted under the following conditions:

The change does not break valid unit tests;

New unit tests cover the bug fix;

The current buggy behavior is not widely used as a “feature”.

Note

When documentation (or PHPDoc) is not in sync with the code, code behavior should always be considered as being the correct one.

Besides bug fixes, other minor changes can be accepted in a patch version:

Performance improvement: Performance improvement should only be accepted if the changes are local (located in one class) and only for algorithmic issues (any such patches must come with numbers that show a significant improvement on real-world code);

Newer versions of PHP: Fixes that add support for newer versions of PHP are acceptable if they don’t break the unit test suite;

Newer versions of popular OSes: Fixes that add support for newer versions of popular OSes (Linux, MacOS and Windows) are acceptable if they don’t break the unit test suite;

Translations: Translation updates and additions are accepted;

External data: Updates for external data included in Symfony can be updated (like ICU for instance);

Version updates for Composer dependencies: Changing the minimal version of a dependency is possible, bumping to a major one or increasing PHP minimal version is not;

Coding standard and refactoring: Coding standard fixes or code refactoring are not recommended but can be accepted for consistency with the existing code base, if they are not too invasive, and if merging them on master would not lead to complex branch merging;

Tests: Tests that increase the code coverage can be added.

Anything not explicitly listed above should be done on the next minor or major version instead (aka the master branch). For instance, the following changes are never accepted in a patch version:

New features;

Backward compatibility breaks: Note that backward compatibility breaks can be done when fixing a security issue if it would not be possible to fix it otherwise;

Support for external platforms: Adding support for new platforms (like Google App Engine) cannot be done in patch versions;

Exception messages: Exception messages must not be changed as some automated systems might rely on them (even if this is not recommended);

Adding new Composer dependencies;

Support for newer major versions of Composer dependencies: Taking into account support for newer versions of an existing dependency is not acceptable.

Web design: Changing the web design of built-in pages like exceptions, the toolbar or the profiler is not allowed.

Note

This policy is designed to enable a continuous upgrade path that allows one to move forward with newest Symfony versions in the safest way. One should be able to move PHP versions, OS or Symfony versions almost independently. That’s the reason why supporting the latest PHP versions or OS features is considered as bug fixes.

Proposing a Change

A pull request, “PR” for short, is the best way to provide a bug fix or to propose enhancements to Symfony.

Step 1: Check existing Issues and Pull Requests

Before working on a change, check to see if someone else also raised the topic or maybe even started working on a PR by searching on GitHub [https://github.com/symfony/symfony/issues?q=+is%3Aopen+].

If you are unsure or if you have any questions during this entire process, please ask your questions on the #contribs channel on Symfony Slack [https://symfony.com/slack-invite].

Step 2: Setup your Environment

Install the Software Stack

Before working on Symfony, setup a friendly environment with the following software:

Git;

PHP version 7.2.5 or above.

Configure Git

Set up your user information with your real name and a working email address:

1
2

|

$ git config --global user.name "Your Name"
$ git config --global user.email you@example.com

Tip

If you are new to Git, you are highly recommended to read the excellent and free ProGit [https://git-scm.com/book] book.

Tip

If your IDE creates configuration files inside the project’s directory, you can use global .gitignore file (for all projects) or .git/info/exclude file (per project) to ignore them. See GitHub’s documentation [https://help.github.com/github/using-git/ignoring-files].

Tip

Windows users: when installing Git, the installer will ask what to do with line endings, and suggests replacing all LF with CRLF. This is the wrong setting if you wish to contribute to Symfony! Selecting the as-is method is your best choice, as Git will convert your line feeds to the ones in the repository. If you have already installed Git, you can check the value of this setting by typing:

1

|

$ git config core.autocrlf

This will return either “false”, “input” or “true”; “true” and “false” being the wrong values. Change it to “input” by typing:

1

|

$ git config --global core.autocrlf input

Replace –global by –local if you want to set it only for the active repository

Get the Symfony Source Code

Get the Symfony source code:

Create a GitHub [https://github.com/join] account and sign in;

Fork the Symfony repository [https://github.com/symfony/symfony] (click on the “Fork” button);

After the “forking action” has completed, clone your fork locally (this will create a symfony directory):

1

|

$ git clone git@github.com:USERNAME/symfony.git

Add the upstream repository as a remote:

1
2

|

$ cd symfony
$ git remote add upstream git://github.com/symfony/symfony.git

Check that the current Tests Pass

Now that Symfony is installed, check that all unit tests pass for your environment as explained in the dedicated document.

Tip

If tests are failing, check on Travis-CI [https://travis-ci.org/symfony/symfony] if the same test is failing there as well. In that case you do not need to be concerned about the test failing locally.

Step 3: Work on your Pull Request

The License

Before you start, you should be aware that all the code you are going to submit must be released under the MIT license.

Choose the right Branch

Before working on a PR, you must determine on which branch you need to work:

4.4, if you are fixing a bug for an existing feature or want to make a change that falls into the list of acceptable changes in patch versions (you may have to choose a higher branch if the feature you are fixing was introduced in a later version);

5.x, if you are adding a new feature.

The only exception is when a new major Symfony version (5.0, 6.0, etc.) comes out every two years. Because of the special development process of those versions, you need to use the previous minor version for the features (e.g. use 4.4 instead of 5.0, use 5.4 instead of 6.0, etc.)

Note

All bug fixes merged into maintenance branches are also merged into more recent branches on a regular basis. For instance, if you submit a PR for the 4.4 branch, the PR will also be applied by the core team on the 5.x branch.

Create a Topic Branch

Each time you want to work on a PR for a bug or on an enhancement, create a topic branch:

1

|

$ git checkout -b BRANCH_NAME 5.x

Or, if you want to provide a bug fix for the 4.4 branch, first track the remote 4.4 branch locally:

1

|

$ git checkout --track origin/4.4

Then create a new branch off the 4.4 branch to work on the bug fix:

1

|

$ git checkout -b BRANCH_NAME 4.4

Tip

Use a descriptive name for your branch (ticket_XXX where XXX is the ticket number is a good convention for bug fixes).

The above checkout commands automatically switch the code to the newly created branch (check the branch you are working on with git branch).

Use your Branch in an Existing Project

If you want to test your code in an existing project that uses symfony/symfony or Symfony components, you can use the link utility provided in the Git repository you cloned previously. This tool scans the vendor/ directory of your project, finds Symfony packages it uses, and replaces them by symbolic links to the ones in the Git repository.

1

|

$ php link /path/to/your/project

Before running the link command, be sure that the dependencies of the project you want to debug are installed by running composer install inside it.

Tip

If symlinks to your local Symfony fork cannot be resolved inside your project due to your dev environment (for instance when using Vagrant where only the current project directory is mounted), you can alternatively use the --copy option. When finishing testing your Symfony code into your project, you can use the --rollback option to make your project back to its original dependencies.

Work on your Pull Request

Work on the code as much as you want and commit as much as you want; but keep in mind the following:

Read about the Symfony conventions and follow the coding standards (use git diff --check to check for trailing spaces – also read the tip below);

Add unit tests to prove that the bug is fixed or that the new feature actually works;

Try hard to not break backward compatibility (if you must do so, try to provide a compatibility layer to support the old way) – PRs that break backward compatibility have less chance to be merged;

Do atomic and logically separate commits (use the power of git rebase to have a clean and logical history);

Never fix coding standards in some existing code as it makes the code review more difficult;

Write good commit messages (see the tip below).

Tip

When submitting pull requests, fabbot [https://fabbot.io] checks your code for common typos and verifies that you are using the PHP coding standards as defined in PSR-1 [https://www.php-fig.org/psr/psr-1/] and PSR-2 [https://www.php-fig.org/psr/psr-2/].

A status is posted below the pull request description with a summary of any problems it detects or any Travis-CI [https://travis-ci.org/symfony/symfony] build failures.

Tip

A good commit message is composed of a summary (the first line), optionally followed by a blank line and a more detailed description. The summary should start with the Component you are working on in square brackets ([DependencyInjection], [FrameworkBundle], …). Use a verb (fixed ..., added ..., …) to start the summary and don’t add a period at the end.

Prepare your Pull Request for Submission

When your PR is not about a bug fix (when you add a new feature or change an existing one for instance), it must also include the following:

An explanation of the changes in the relevant CHANGELOG file(s) (the [BC BREAK] or the [DEPRECATION] prefix must be used when relevant);

An explanation on how to upgrade an existing application in the relevant UPGRADE file(s) if the changes break backward compatibility or if you deprecate something that will ultimately break backward compatibility.

Step 4: Submit your Pull Request

Whenever you feel that your PR is ready for submission, follow the following steps.

Rebase your Pull Request

Before submitting your PR, update your branch (needed if it takes you a while to finish your changes):

1
2
3
4
5

|

$ git checkout 5.x
$ git fetch upstream
$ git merge upstream/5.x
$ git checkout BRANCH_NAME
$ git rebase 5.x

Tip

Replace 5.x with the branch you selected previously (e.g. 4.4) if you are working on a bug fix.

When doing the rebase command, you might have to fix merge conflicts. git status will show you the unmerged files. Resolve all the conflicts, then continue the rebase:

1
2

|

$ git add ... # add resolved files
$ git rebase --continue

Check that all tests still pass and push your branch remotely:

1

|

$ git push --force origin BRANCH_NAME

Make a Pull Request

You can now make a pull request on the symfony/symfony GitHub repository.

Tip

Take care to point your pull request towards symfony:4.4 if you want the core team to pull a bug fix based on the 4.4 branch.

To ease the core team work, always include the modified components in your pull request message, like in:

1
2

|

[Yaml] fixed something
[Form] [Validator] [FrameworkBundle] added something

The default pull request description contains a table which you must fill in with the appropriate answers. This ensures that contributions may be reviewed without needless feedback loops and that your contributions can be included into Symfony as quickly as possible.

Some answers to the questions trigger some more requirements:

If you answer yes to “Bug fix?”, check if the bug is already listed in the Symfony issues and reference it/them in “Fixed tickets”;

If you answer yes to “New feature?”, you must submit a pull request to the documentation and reference it under the “Doc PR” section;

If you answer yes to “BC breaks?”, the PR must contain updates to the relevant CHANGELOG and UPGRADE files;

If you answer yes to “Deprecations?”, the PR must contain updates to the relevant CHANGELOG and UPGRADE files;

If you answer no to “Tests pass”, you must add an item to a todo-list with the actions that must be done to fix the tests;

If the “license” is not MIT, just don’t submit the pull request as it won’t be accepted anyway.

If some of the previous requirements are not met, create a todo-list and add relevant items:

1
2
3

|

- [ ] fix the tests as they have not been updated yet
- [ ] submit changes to the documentation
- [ ] document the BC breaks

If the code is not finished yet because you don’t have time to finish it or because you want early feedback on your work, add an item to todo-list:

1
2

|

- [ ] finish the code
- [ ] gather feedback for my changes

As long as you have items in the todo-list, please prefix the pull request title with “[WIP]”. If you do not yet want to trigger the automated tests, you can also set the PR to draft status [https://help.github.com/github/collaborating-with-issues-and-pull-requests/about-pull-requests#draft-pull-requests].

In the pull request description, give as much detail as possible about your changes (don’t hesitate to give code examples to illustrate your points). If your pull request is about adding a new feature or modifying an existing one, explain the rationale for the changes. The pull request description helps the code review and it serves as a reference when the code is merged (the pull request description and all its associated comments are part of the merge commit message).

In addition to this “code” pull request, you must also send a pull request to the documentation repository [https://github.com/symfony/symfony-docs] to update the documentation when appropriate.

Step 5: Receiving Feedback

We ask all contributors to follow some best practices to ensure a constructive feedback process.

If you think someone fails to keep this advice in mind and you want another perspective, please join the #contribs channel on Symfony Slack [https://symfony.com/slack-invite]. If you receive feedback you find abusive please contact the CARE team.

The core team is responsible for deciding which PR gets merged, so their feedback is the most relevant. So do not feel pressured to refactor your code immediately when someone provides feedback.

Rework your Pull Request

Based on the feedback on the pull request, you might need to rework your PR. Before re-submitting the PR, rebase with upstream/5.x or upstream/4.4, don’t merge; and force the push to the origin:

1
2

|

$ git rebase -f upstream/5.x
$ git push --force origin BRANCH_NAME

Note

When doing a push --force, always specify the branch name explicitly to avoid messing other branches in the repository (--force tells Git that you really want to mess with things so do it carefully).

Moderators earlier asked you to “squash” your commits. This means you will convert many commits to one commit. This is no longer necessary today, because Symfony project uses a proprietary tool which automatically squashes all commits before merging.

Creating a Bug Reproducer

The main Symfony code repository receives thousands of issues reports per year. Some of those issues are easy to understand and the Symfony Core developers can fix them without any other information. However, other issues are much harder to understand because developers can’t reproduce them in their computers. That’s when we’ll ask you to create a “bug reproducer”, which is the minimum amount of code needed to make the bug appear when executed.

Reproducing Simple Bugs

If you are reporting a bug related to some Symfony component used outside the Symfony framework, it’s enough to share a small PHP script that when executed shows the bug:

// First, run "composer require symfony/validator"
// Then, execute this file:
<?php
require_once __DIR__.'/vendor/autoload.php';
use Symfony\Component\Validator\Constraints;

$wrongUrl = 'http://example.com/exploit.html?<script>alert(1);</script>';
$urlValidator = new Constraints\UrlValidator();
$urlConstraint = new Constraints\Url();

// The URL is wrong, so var_dump() should display an error, but it displays
// "null" instead because there is no context to build a validator violation
var_dump($urlValidator->validate($wrongUrl, $urlConstraint));

Reproducing Complex Bugs

If the bug is related to the Symfony Framework or if it’s too complex to create a PHP script, it’s better to reproduce the bug by creating a new project. To do so:

Create a new project:

1

|

$ composer create-project symfony/skeleton bug_app

Add and commit the changes generated by Symfony.

Now you must add the minimum amount of code to reproduce the bug. This is the trickiest part and it’s explained a bit more later.

Add and commit your changes.

Create a new repository [https://github.com/new] on GitHub (give it any name).

Follow the instructions on GitHub to add the origin remote to your local project and push it.

Add a comment in your original issue report to share the URL of your forked project (e.g. https://github.com/YOUR-GITHUB-USERNAME/symfony_issue_23567) and, if necessary, explain the steps to reproduce (e.g. “browse this URL”, “fill in this data in the form and submit it”, etc.)

Adding the Minimum Amount of Code Possible

The key to create a bug reproducer is to solely focus on the feature that you suspect is failing. For example, imagine that you suspect that the bug is related to a route definition. Then, after creating your project:

Don’t edit any of the default Symfony configuration options.

Don’t copy your original application code and don’t use the same structure of controllers, actions, etc. as in your original application.

Create a small controller and add your routing definition that shows the bug.

Don’t create or modify any other file.

Install the local web server provided by Symfony and use the symfony server:start command to browse to the new route and see if the bug appears or not.

If you can see the bug, you’re done and you can already share the code with us.

If you can’t see the bug, you must keep making small changes. For example, if your original route was defined using XML, forget about the previous route and define the route using XML instead. Or maybe your application registers some event listeners and that’s where the real bug is. In that case, add an event listener that’s similar to your real app to see if you can find the bug.

In short, the idea is to keep adding small and incremental changes to a new project until you can reproduce the bug.

Security Issues

This document explains how Symfony security issues are handled by the Symfony core team (Symfony being the code hosted on the main symfony/symfony Git repository [https://github.com/symfony/symfony]).

Reporting a Security Issue

If you think that you have found a security issue in Symfony, don’t use the bug tracker and don’t publish it publicly. Instead, all security issues must be sent to security [at] symfony.com. Emails sent to this address are forwarded to the Symfony core team private mailing-list.

Resolving Process

For each report, we first try to confirm the vulnerability. When it is confirmed, the core team works on a solution following these steps:

Send an acknowledgment to the reporter;

Work on a patch;

Get a CVE identifier from mitre.org [https://cveform.mitre.org/];

Write a security announcement for the official Symfony blog [https://symfony.com/blog/] about the vulnerability. This post should contain the following information:

a title that always include the “Security release” string;

a description of the vulnerability;

the affected versions;

the possible exploits;

how to patch/upgrade/workaround affected applications;

the CVE identifier;

credits.

Send the patch and the announcement to the reporter for review;

Apply the patch to all maintained versions of Symfony;

Package new versions for all affected versions;

Publish the post on the official Symfony blog [https://symfony.com/blog/] (it must also be added to the “Security Advisories [https://symfony.com/blog/category/security-advisories]” category);

Update the public security advisories database [https://github.com/FriendsOfPHP/security-advisories] maintained by the FriendsOfPHP organization and which is used by the check:security command.

Note

Releases that include security issues should not be done on Saturday or Sunday, except if the vulnerability has been publicly posted.

Note

While we are working on a patch, please do not reveal the issue publicly.

Note

The resolution takes anywhere between a couple of days to a month depending on its complexity and the coordination with the downstream projects (see next paragraph).

Collaborating with Downstream Open-Source Projects

As Symfony is used by many large Open-Source projects, we standardized the way the Symfony security team collaborates on security issues with downstream projects. The process works as follows:

After the Symfony security team has acknowledged a security issue, it immediately sends an email to the downstream project security teams to inform them of the issue;

The Symfony security team creates a private Git repository to ease the collaboration on the issue and access to this repository is given to the Symfony security team, to the Symfony contributors that are impacted by the issue, and to one representative of each downstream projects;

All people with access to the private repository work on a solution to solve the issue via pull requests, code reviews, and comments;

Once the fix is found, all involved projects collaborate to find the best date for a joint release (there is no guarantee that all releases will be at the same time but we will try hard to make them at about the same time). When the issue is not known to be exploited in the wild, a period of two weeks is considered a reasonable amount of time.

The list of downstream projects participating in this process is kept as small as possible in order to better manage the flow of confidential information prior to disclosure. As such, projects are included at the sole discretion of the Symfony security team.

As of today, the following projects have validated this process and are part of the downstream projects included in this process:

Drupal (releases typically happen on Wednesdays)

eZPublish

Issue Severity

In order to determine the severity of a security issue we take into account the complexity of any potential attack, the impact of the vulnerability and also how many projects it is likely to affect. This score out of 15 is then converted into a level of: Low, Medium, High, Critical, or Exceptional.

Attack Complexity

Score of between 1 and 5 depending on how complex it is to exploit the vulnerability

4 - 5 Basic: attacker must follow a set of simple steps

2 - 3 Complex: attacker must follow non-intuitive steps with a high level of dependencies

1 - 2 High: A successful attack depends on conditions beyond the attacker’s control. That is, a successful attack cannot be accomplished at will, but requires the attacker to invest in some measurable amount of effort in preparation or execution against the vulnerable component before a successful attack can be expected.

Impact

Scores from the following areas are added together to produce a score. The score for Impact is capped at 6. Each area is scored between 0 and 4.

Integrity: Does this vulnerability cause non-public data to be accessible? If so, does the attacker have control over the data disclosed? (0-4)

Disclosure: Can this exploit allow system data (or data handled by the system) to be compromised? If so, does the attacker have control over modification? (0-4)

Code Execution: Does the vulnerability allow arbitrary code to be executed on an end-users system, or the server that it runs on? (0-4)

Availability: Is the availability of a service or application affected? Is it reduced availability or total loss of availability of a service / application? Availability includes networked services (e.g., databases) or resources such as consumption of network bandwidth, processor cycles, or disk space. (0-4)

Affected Projects

Scores from the following areas are added together to produce a score. The score for Affected Projects is capped at 4.

Will it affect some or all using a component? (1-2)

Is the usage of the component that would cause such a thing already considered bad practice? (0-1)

How common/popular is the component (e.g. Console vs HttpFoundation vs Lock)? (0-2)

Are a number of well-known open source projects using Symfony affected that requires coordinated releases? (0-1)

Score Totals

Attack Complexity: 1 - 5

Impact: 1 - 6

Affected Projects: 1 - 4

Severity levels

Low: 1 - 5

Medium: 6 - 10

High: 11 - 12

Critical: 13 - 14

Exceptional: 15

Security Advisories

Tip

You can check your Symfony application for known security vulnerabilities using the check:security command.

Check the Security Advisories [https://symfony.com/blog/category/security-advisories] blog category for a list of all security vulnerabilities that were fixed in Symfony releases, starting from Symfony 1.0.0.